中文字幕｜dottob
- Subtitled by CrazyIvan -
顶峰娱乐
狮门公司
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
跨河图像
德马雷斯特电影
银色图像
钢锯+岭
一个真实的故事
《以赛亚书》40章28节
你可曾听过
Have you not heard?
《以赛亚书》40章28节
耶和华是永恒之神
The Lord is the everlasting God.
创造地极之主
the Creator of the ends of the earth.
他既不疲乏，也不困倦
He will not grow tired or weary.
他的智慧无人可揣度
And his understanding no one can fathom.
《以赛亚书》40章29节
他赐力量予疲乏者
He gives strength to the weary
《以赛亚书》40章29节
增能力予软弱者
And increases the power of the weak.
《以赛亚书》40章30节
正值青春亦会疲惫困倦
Even youths grow tired and weary,
《以赛亚书》40章30节
青年亦会绊倒跌跤
And young man stumble and fall
《以赛亚书》40章31节
但那些仰望上帝者
But those who hope in the Lord.
《以赛亚书》40章31节
必重新得力
Will renew their strength.
他们必展翅翱翔如鹰
They will soar on wings like eagles.
他们必奔跑
They will run
而不疲倦
And not grow weary.
他们必行走
They will walk
而不跌倒
And not be faint.
德斯蒙德
Desmond.
坚持住
Hang on.
坚持住，德斯蒙德
Hang on, Desmond.
我们会带你离开这儿
We're gonna get you outta here.
蓝脊山脉，弗吉尼亚州
十六年前
德斯蒙德
Desmond.
干嘛
What.
等等嘛
Wait up.
跟上嘛
Catch up.
等等嘛，我有事要告诉你
Wait up. I got something to tell you.
什么？哈尔
What Hal?
到顶者赢
Race you to the top.
嘿，骗子
Hey cheater.
回头见，迟钝
See you later slowpoke.
嘿
Hey.
搭把手
Wanna hand?
我能行
I got it.
救了你
Saved you ah.
啊，你别，死吧
Ah, you don't. Quit it.
你死吧
You quit it.
上帝保佑
God sake.
嘿，离悬崖远点
Hey, get away from that ledge.
该死的傻仔
You damn fool kids.
想摔断脖子吗
You gonna break your neck.
他们是多斯的儿子
It's them Doss's kids.
跟老爹一样疯狂
Crazy as their old man.
他们挖掘了杰克埋骨之地
They dug up the corner of Jack's remain.
把他放在人行道上
Put him in the sidewalk.
你们现已认不出来啦
You boys won't recognize it now.
告诉你，我怀疑他们会认出你
Mind you I doubt they'll recognize you.
他们几乎认不出我，当我路过
They hardly know me when I walked by.
好象我跟你一起死了
It's like I died with you.
好象我们从未存在过
It's like we boys never existed.
好了，今天就说这些
Well that's all I got for you today.
用右手挡住他，德斯蒙德
Block him with your right Desmond.
别打了
Stop it.
听到了吗
Do you hear me.
他们干嘛打架
What are they fighting about?
他们何需有理
When did they ever needed a reason.
嘿汤姆，你能…
Hey Tom do you
何必阻止而让我两个都打
Why stop and save me whipping them both.
这样我只需打那个赢的
This way I'd whip the one that wins.
汤姆
Tom.
不
No.
噢天啦
Oh God.
汤姆
Tom.
醒醒，你能听到吗
Wake up. Can you hear me?
你怎么能这样
What the hell did you done?
他听不到了
He can't hear me.
我们得拿些冰块
We'll get some ice.
把那个篮子拿开
You shift that basket.
好的
I got it.
他在呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
哈尔
Hal?
哈尔你能听到吗
Hal can you hear me?
哈尔
Hal?
拜托
Come on.
上帝救救他
God help him.
哈尔
Hal?
《主祷文 十诫》
Lord's Prayer Ten Commandments Vintage
你做事不经大脑吗
What do you think you doing?
我现在必须打你，你知道规则
I'm going to have to beat you now. You know the rules.
听到没，德斯蒙德
You hear me Desmond?
第六诫 你不能杀人
SIXTH COMMANDMENT Thou shalt not kill
德斯蒙德
Desmond !
汤姆，住手
Tom. Stop.
这样教育不了他，他的暴行已经够多了
It's not going to teach the boy. His violence enough already.
好极了，赏他一个令人窒息的吻
Ok fine, you go smothering and kiss him.
告诉他这世界是个既柔软又温暖之处
You tell him the world is soft and gentle place.
哈尔会好的
Hal's gonna be okay.
嘿
Hey.
我差点杀了他
I could've killed him.
是的，你差点
Yes, you could have.
谋杀是众恶之首
Murder is the worst sin of all.
取人性命
And to take another man's life.
则是最严重之罪在主眼里
That is the most egregious sin in Lord's eye.
再没别的能令他更伤心
Nothing hurts His heart the most.
我恨他
I hate him.
妈妈
Mama.
他为什么如此恨我们
Why does he hate us so much?
哦，他不恨我们
Oh he don't hate us.
他恨自己
He hates himself
有时
Sometimes
你爸爸，我见过真实的他
Your daddy and I met the real him.
我希望你了解他，就像战前我那样
I wish you knew him like I did before the war.
十五年后
我们唱得如何？德斯蒙德
How do we sound Desmond?
就像天使，妈
Like a heavenly host angels, Mom.
你知，撒谎可是罪喔
Now you know it's a sin to tell a lie.
尤其在此地
Especially in this place.
我可从未说过她们是唱歌的天使
Well I never said they were singing angels.
外面怎么了？德斯蒙德
What's going on out there, Desmond?
继续，拉出来，拉出来
Go on. Get him out. Get him out.
拖出来
Drag him out.
拖吧
Just tug.
我打电话叫救护车
I'll phone an ambulance.
不！没时间了
No. No time.
找辆皮卡
Just a pickup
要快
Quick.
好的
Okay.
林奇伯格医院
LYNCHBURG HOSPITAL
你会好的，伙计，你会好的
You gonna be fine, man. You gonna be fine.
你有专家罩
You in good hand.
何处受伤
What do we got here?
动脉切断
That's a severed artery.
- 拿些缝线来  - 好的，医生
- Get some sutures.  - Yes, doctor.
稍稍用力按住它
Put some pressure on it.
是你用此止血的
Did you apply this tourniquet?
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
干得不错，你可救了这娃一命
Nice work. You might've save this boy's life.
你住我们这儿，你会好的
You staying with us. You'll be okay.
我们来吧
We can get that.
住我们这儿，你会好的
Stay with us. You should be okay.
你感觉好吗
You feel okay?
当然，医生
Certainly doc.
部队体检在那边，这里是献血
Army physical is that way. This is for giving blood.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
哦不，那不是我的
Oh no. That's not mine.
我很好
I'm fine.
谢谢你的问询，女士
Thank you for asking though maam.
你要什么
What do you need?
我的皮带
My belt.
我把它借给出车祸的男生
I lend it to the boy who had the accident.
没它我的裤子系不好
My pants don't hold up so good without it.
呃，我可没有你的皮带
Well I dont' have your belt.
不，我知女士，它仍在男生那儿
No. I know that maam. It's out there with the boys still.
好吧
Okay.
我在此采血
I'm just here to take blood.
我给你我的
I'll give you mine.
好吧
Okay.
去那个房间，跟别人一起等
Go to that room over there. Wait with the others.
我会叫你
I'll call you.
那个，那个房间
That. That room.
你以前献过血吗，先生…
You ever given blood before, Mr.
多斯
Doss.
但朋友们都叫我德斯蒙德，不，女士这是我第一次
But my friends call me Desmond. No, maam this is my first time.
封面是红胁蓝尾鸲(qú)
多萝西·舒特《北美珍禽》
Dorothy Schutte《RARE BIRDS of North America》
我总梦想成为医生，只是呢
I always dream about being a doctor but ahhh
没念多少书
Didn't get much school.
可能有点头晕，采完后
Might be a little dizzy when we're done.
有人接你吗
Somebody picking you up?
没，女士，我走回去
No, maam. I'm walking back.
你住哪儿
Where do you live?
福特哈姆，女士
Fort Ham, Maam.
那挺远的
That's away.
五或六英里
Five or six miles.
我穿过树林
I cut through the woods.
那就七英里
Seven that way.
必是因喜欢树林
Must really like the woods.
是的女士，确实是
Yes maam. Sure do.
好吧
Okay.
轻压此处
Put some pressure here.
你没事吧
You okay?
这是要去哪儿？看起来整洁帅气
Where are you going looking all spruce and nice?
去见昨天的某人
Met someone yesterday.
医院护士，名叫多萝西舒特，我要娶她
Nurse over at the hospital name Dorothy Schutte and I'm gonna marry her.
天啦，她知道吗
Goodness, does she know that?
尚未知但将知
Well not yet but about to.
你有说过话吗？跟女人
Do you have even spoken to a woman?
除了这个尚未成家者
Other than the one that's not family.
跟她说过
Spoke to her.
既如此，给你兄弟来个大大的拥抱
In that case, come give your brother a big hug.
呕哈尔！让你的油爪离我远点儿
Oh Hal. Get your greasy paws off of me.
祝我好运，妈妈
Wish me luck mama.
祝你好运
Good luck.
下一个
Next.
随便坐
Grab a seat.
你以前献过血吗
You ever been given blood before?
是的女士我有
Yes maam I have.
你，皮带男
You the belt man.
德斯蒙德，就是我
Desmond that's me.
好吧，德斯蒙德，我们不能连续两天采你的血
Well Desmond we can't take your blood two days in a row.
那就好，可否拿回我的
That's good. Can we get mine back?
你的啥
You what?
我的血，我想要回它
My blood I need it back.
那不行，不能把它还你
It dont work like that. We can't just give it back to you.
好吧，你必需还
Well you got to.
自从你用针扎了我，我就心跳加速
Ever since you stuck me with that needle my heart is beating up fast.
每次想到你则会跳得更快
Everytime I think about you beat faster still.
我以前从未听过这话
I never heard that one before.
好老土
It's pretty corny.
是土
It is.
对啊
Yeah.
这是个耻辱，我练了一整夜
That's a shame. I've been practicing that all night.
不好吗
No good?
我没那样说
I didn't say that.
有何差异？动脉跟静脉
What's the difference between an artery and a vein?
你说啥
What are you talking about?
男孩的车祸
The boy's accident.
动脉喷血
Arteries spurt blood.
静脉呢
And veins?
流血
Bleed.
我觉得你得多练习男生跟
I think you need to practice your boys and
女生的约会对白，在你出门前
girls dating talk at home before you come out.
我可能练过
I probably do.
我给你本书，若你那样有兴趣
I give you a book if you that interested.
约会时
On dating?
喷血时
On blood.
二战供应兵招募海报
We Soldiers of Supply pledge that  our fighting men shall not want
美国政府 奉献 大战序幕
the UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT presents PRELUDE TO WAR
还有个医学问题？可能
Another medical question perhaps?
没，我只觉得你是我见过的最漂亮的
No, I just think you're the prettiest thing I ever seen.
那是因为我四周黑麻麻地
That's cause I'm sitting in the dark.
不
No.
你确实美丽
And you're beautiful.
让路
Out of the way!
你得看好路再走
You need to watch where you going.
对不起，我没想到你会介意
I'm sorry I didn't think you mind.
你没问过
You didn't ask.
我想你可能会喜欢
I thought you might've like it.
我可能会，如果你问了
Well I might've if you asked.
你来吗
You coming?
死开
Shit!
你为何对我们只字不提
Why didn't you say anything to us?
因为你会试着让我说出来，亦知我做得对
Cause you would've try and talk me out of it and know what I'm doing is right.
那主的诫命呢
And what about His commandment?
在战争中那不是杀戮
It's not killing in a war.
我是保护许多从我们教会入伍的男孩
I woud protected lots of boys from our church going.
战事已起，他们要人
There's a war and they need men.
在造纸厂上班救不了国
Working in a paper mill aren't going to save this country.
看起来就像影星
Looks like a movie star.
哈啊孩子
Huh boy?
制服好看
Nice uniform.
帽子不错
Good hat.
提醒了我，哈代穿这身制服是啥样，当我们奔赴法国
Reminds me how Hardy get in his look in this uniform when we went to France.
还记得他吗？多萝西
Remember him Dorothy?
不要，汤姆
Don't Tom.
什么
What?
我只是说哈尔穿起制服看着如何时髦
I'm just saying how snappy Hal looks in his uniform.
而所有的女孩似乎都这么认为
All you girls certainly seems to think so.
他使她们涌向他，他得意之极
He had them flocking to him. He was most proud.
我只希望哈尔中枪时，是穿过夹克前面
I just hope that when Hal get shot it's through the front of his jacket.
像个简单射伤，不足为虑
Like a simple entry wound not what you miss.
若是击中背部
Or'd got hit in the back.
把他的大部分内脏跟肠子从前面炸出落得到处都是
It blew most of his guts and intestines out his front off for everywhere.
彻底毁掉他的制服
Wrecked his uniform entirely.
好彩他死了，所以他从不知他的制服看上去有多糟
It was lucky he was dead so he never knew how awful his uniform looked.
离开我的视线
Get out of my sight.
你藏了啥？高山护卫
What are you park mountain guard?
你不帮我吗？德斯蒙德·多斯
Are you gonna help me Desmond Doss?
或者你只想让我困住
Or you just gonna leave me stranded?
我会帮你的
I'll help you.
但你得付出代价
But it's gonna cost you.
什么
What?
亲一个
A kiss.
这纯粹是敲诈
That is pure blackmail.
是的，女士，但那仍是我的条件
Well yes maam it is but that is still my condition.
事实上
As indeed,
我想抱着你亲
I gonna hold you to it.
等等
Hold on now.
你不会打我？是吗
You ain't gonna slap me are you?
因我可能会带着你跟我掉下去
Cause I'll fall off I'm gonna take you with me.
吻我即知
Kiss me and find out.
《坎宁安实用解剖学手册》
CUNNINGHAM'S MANUAL OF PRACTICL ANATOMY
什么
What?
我得参军
I have to enlist.
我不能留在这儿而让他们都为我而战
I can't stay here while all them go fight for me.
是的，你能
Yes, you can.
- 你能留在这儿  - 多萝西，我必须
- You can stay here.  - Dorothy I have to.
我要当军医
I will be a medic.
我指我是去救人而非杀人
I figure I'll be saving people not killing.
我得上班了，不想迟到
I have to go to work and don't want to be late.
多萝西，别这样
Dorothy. Don't.
多萝西，多萝西
Dorothy. Dorothy.
那么你想求我嫁给你还是别的
So are you gonna ask me to marry you or what?
我不知你会否还讨厌我
I don't know you still gonna hate me?
我也不知，你可没问
I wouldn't know you haven't ask.
那我来问你
Well I'm asking you
全心全意地，你愿意嫁给我吗
With all my heart. Will you marry me?
那当然
Then yes.
是的，我愿意
Yes I will.
何时
When?
待到你首次出征时
Soon as you get your first leave.
但我此刻仍不喜欢你
But I still don't like you at this moment.
对啊
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
我爱你
I love you.
嘘…
Shhhh.
妈妈说在这儿能见到你
Mama say come see you here.
这三位是我最好的朋友
These three were my bestfriends.
爱德华·米勒
弗吉尼亚州人
1900年生于林奇伯格
1918年死于法国贝洛伍德
为国捐躯
我们一起长大
I grew up with them.
一起惹麻烦，一起追女生
Got into trouble with them. Chase girls with them.
我们一起参军
I enlisted with them.
然后吾友们长眠于此
Then my friends are there.
泥草覆身，虫蛆啃噬
Covered in dirt and grass eaten by worms.
我不想探望我崽于此
I don't want to have to visit my sons here.
爸爸我已签约
Daddy I signed up already.
我别无选择除了入伍
I couldn't do otherwise pop.
- 人人都这样  - 你并非人人
- Everybody else is doing it.  - You ain't everybody else.
人人忙做事
Everybody else jumps in does thing quick
不加思索有如我们这种该死的蠢货
without thinking like damn idiot fools we were.
你可知活着的士兵所以活着，只因他们能思考，你不能
You know that soldiers who live they live cause they can do that. You can't!
你得坐下思考，凡事祷告
You got to sit and think and pray about everything.
看看你，你现在就想想
Look at you. You're doing it right now.
你无法靠自己活着，如果你去
You won't be able to live with yourself if you go.
不，我无法靠自己活着，假如我不去
No, I won't be able to live with myself if I don't.
我要当个军医
I'm going to be a medic.
那将是我服役的方式
That's going to be my way to serve.
那你就去把它想清楚
There you go thinking it all out.
你以为这场战争会让你称心如意
What you figure this war is going to fit in with you?
如你所愿
Your ideas?
我只晓得我不怀疑这会很难
What I know I don't doubt it's going to be hard.
不是难，是不可能
It won't be hard. It will be impossible.
无论如何
You know whatever.
如今你那疯狂脑子里的信仰
beliefs you had in your crazy head now.
它们永不发生，不起作用
They don't ever play out it don't work that way.
如有某些我所不知的奇遇
And if by certain I don't know miracle chance
你活下来
you survive
你不会把感谢给上帝
you won't be giving no thanks to God.
休息下，休息下，我们都需要一些空气
Break. Break. We all need some air.
来吧伙计们，迈迈腿，我理解你得跟老妈说再见
C'mon fellas shake a leg. I'd understand you got to say goodbye to mama.
来吧
C'mon.
女士们，拜托！远离公共汽车
Ladies please! Step away from the bus.
我差点忘了
I almost forgot.
我非得找根撬棍吗？
Do I need a crowbar?
拿着
Here.
我要你带上这个
I want you to have this.
它是我的
It's mine.
你把它放在这儿
You keep it right here.
我就在那儿
Where I'll be.
我爱你
I love you.
回到我身边，德斯蒙德·多斯，我爱你
Come Back To Me, Desmond Doss I Love You.
杰克逊堡
FORT JACKSON
我非得盯着你的畸形吗？每次我走到床上
Do I have to gaze at your deformity everytime I walk to my bed.
眼红吧，我的朋友
Gaze upon it in envy my friend.
你还好吗
You okay there?
你好象迷了路
You look lost.
要不你就坐这儿
Or you can sit right here.
不错的选择
Nice choice.
那儿能从高山看到大湖
It got views to the mountain down to lake.
兰德尔·富勒
Randall Fuller.
德斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
叫他“教授”
Call him 'Teach'.
你听不懂他说的每个字
You won't understand a word he says.
因为这儿没人懂
That because no one else here can read.
那对睾丸的主人自称“好莱坞”
But testicles there belong to a man calling himself 'Hollywood'.
它们看起来更像是属于小家伙
They look like they belong to a smaller guy.
你懂睾丸
You know testicles.
哦嘿
Oh hey.
我刚买这双鞋
I just got this shoes.
嘿呀
Hey ya.
格雷斯·诺兰，来自雷德伍德，你呢
Grease Nolan out of Redwood. Where you from?
- 维吉尼亚  - 威尔·比利哈
- Virginia.  - Will Billy huh?
你娶了你第一个表妹
You marry your first cousin?
哈哈开个玩笑
Haha just joking.
哇
Woah!
那边的史密提跟科恩斯基臭味相投
That Smitty over there with Kirzinski's ass.
好象你更牛？杂烩脑
Like you were doing any better, chowder head.
嘿，我可不想使你丢脸
Hey, I didn't want to embarassed you.
沃尔·科恩斯基，很高兴见到你
Wal Kirzinski. Nice to meet you.
嘿！乒乓
Hey Ping Pong.
你说你名字是啥？
What you say your name was?
德斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
边上那位是德克萨斯·刘易斯
That Texas Lewis over there.
当他是某类牛仔
Thinks he some kind of cowboy.
还有维托·雷诺利
And Vito Rinnelli.
他也许个小，但他可是斗牛犬
Now he maybe small but he is a bulldog.
- 嗨，你好吗？ - 德斯蒙德
- Hi how you doing?  - Desmond.
这位帅哥是幸运的福特
This handsome guy right here is Lucky Ford.
嘿！
Hey.
那边是沃克和平尼克，他们自诩为洗牌手
That's Walker and Pinnick over there. Pretending they're card shufflers.
安静，格雷斯，好吗
Pipe down Grease alright.
除非你想被钱塞住嘴
Unless you want to put money where your mouth is.
噢嘿
Oh hey.
好书，对吧
Good Book right?
- 对的  - 我觉得是
- Right.  - I think ahh
我觉得“幸运”也有本好书，是吗？“幸运”
I think Lucky's got a good book, right Lucky?
这书好看
It's a good read.
立正！
Attention!
啊！
Ow!
列队，行动
Line up. Move it.
一起来，行动，行动
Let's go. Move it. Move it.
你看起来很怪，你不介意我这样说吧？列兵
You're a strange looking individual if you don't mind me saying so Private?
姓名
Name?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
你死多久了？孩子
How long have you been dead son?
长官
Sir?
我不是长官
I am not "Sir".
我是豪厄尔中士或军士
I am Sergeant Howell or Sarge.
“长官”是叫没用的人
"Sir " you say for useless people.
你的名字是“食尸鬼”你知
The name is Ghoul you see.
沃克
Walker.
中士
Sergeant.
是
It is.
是的，中士
Yes, Sergeant.
你的表演有失常态，列兵
There's something off with your presentation Private.
很难说
Can't place it.
是你的头发
Is it your hair?
还是你裤子上的皱纹
Is it the wrinkle in your trousers?
我脚上插着刀，中士
I have a knife in my foot Sergeant.
噢，是的，当然，是这把刀
Oh yes. Of course. That's it the knife.
你叫什么名字？士兵
What is your name soldier?
史密提·瑞克
Smitty Riker.
不，你的名字是“列兵白痴”
No. Your name is Private Idiot.
你可知为何
You know why?
因为我脚上插着刀
Cause I have a knife in my foot.
谁会把刀插在哪儿？列兵
Who place the knife there Private?
这是个意外，中士，我在练拉伸
It was an accident Sergeant. I was playing stretch.
据我所知你不是有意插在那儿
I'm hardened by the knowledge you did not placed it there with intention.
谁扔的刀
Who threw the knife?
是我，中士
I did Sergeant.
列兵科恩斯基
Private Kirzinski.
你是印地安部族
You're part Indian.
你属哪个部落？孩子
What tribe do you belong, son?
不知道，我是波兰人
Don't know I'm polish.
错
Wrong.
我相信你一定有切诺基族或肖尼族血统
I believe you must have Cherokee or Shawnee blood in you.
- 不，长官  - 你在反驳我
- No Sir.  - Are you contradicting me?
你这婊崽子
You son of a bitch.
不，中士
No sergeant.
让我见识下你的印第安战嚎孩子
Let me see your Indian war cry son.
我不会
I don't.
你的动物图腾是啥
What is your animal spirit?
- 你是乌梢蛇？ - 不，中士
- Are you a Garter snake?  - No Sergeant.
- 你是花栗鼠？ - 不，中士
- Are you a chipmunk?  - No, sergeant.
- 你是跳舞的驯鹿？ - 不，中士
- Are you a dancing reindeer?  - No sergeant.
- 你在反驳我，中士？ - 不，中士
- Are you contradicting me Private?  - No sargeant.
好
Good.
那我从此叫你“酋长”
Then I shall henceforth call you Chief.
作为向你族人致以崇高敬意的标识
As a sign of great respect to your people.
谢谢你，中士
Thank you, sergeant.
你在咧嘴笑我孩子？还是你经常这样
Are you grinning at me boy or is that your natural state?
不，中士
No Sergeant.
姓名，列兵
Name private.
德斯蒙德·多斯
Desmond Doss.
我看库存的玉米都有更好的体质
I have seen stocks of corn with better physiques.
让你想扯掉哪只耳朵，列兵
Makes you wanna pull an ear off Private.
你撑得住体重吗
Can you carry your weight?
是，中士
Yes Sergeant.
对你来说肯定轻松
Should be easy for you then.
下士
Corporal.
你要确保此人远离强风
Make sure you keep this man away from strong winds.
是，中士
Yes, Sergeant.
- 列兵“白痴”  - 是，中士
- Private idiot.  - Yes Sergeant.
把脚抬高
Raise your foot.
更高
Higher.
全部出去，马上
Everyone outside now.
行动
Move it.
我说了行动
I said move it.
我得穿制服，中士
I'm just getting my uniform Sarge.
我有叫他穿吗？下士
Did I asked him to Corporal?
不记得，中士
No memory of it Sarge.
我相信任何为自己自然裸露而如此骄傲的男人
I believe any man who take such pride in his natural naked state.
肯定会享受户外的清爽
Will surely enjoy the brisk of the outdoors.
现在放开你的私处，列兵帕兹
Now move your private, Private Parts.
行动
Move it.
你这个裸露崽子
You son of an exhibitionist.
我要教你们怎么结单套
I'm gonna teach you how to tie a bowline knot.
这样你们能够把你的懒屁股从高处放下
So you can get your sorry asses down from a height.
好让我能踢它们
So I may then can kick 'em.
绕成一个圈
Create a loop.
这是兔子窝
This is the rabbit hole.
兔子出了窝
The rabbit comes out of his hole.
绕着树子跑
Runs around the tree.
回到兔子窝
Goes back into the hole.
完成
Alright.
一起做
Let's go.
很好德克萨斯
Very good Texas.
继续努力，“教授”
Keep struggling Teach.
你从没套过山羊吗，“好莱坞”
Have you ever rope a goat, Hollywood?
没有军士
No Sarge.
- 你从没瞪过山羊眼？ - 没有中士
- Have you ever looked into a goat's eye.  - No sarge.
好，那才不正常
Good. That would be unnatural.
你懂如不吸气必得死
You know if you don't breath you'll die.
不错，列兵“白痴”
Good Private Idiot.
恭喜你老油条，你刚掉了五十英尺，摔断了脖子
Congratulations Greaseball, you just fell fifty feet and broke your neck.
棒极了
Brialliant.
列兵维托·雷诺利
Private Vito Rinnelli.
你勒死自己毫无怜悯
You strangle yourself none mercy.
你是贝内利的粉丝
Are you a fan of Benelli?
不，中士
No Sergeant.
弄高些
Get taller.
你是美国人你会更高些
You're American you'd be taller.
这是什么，多斯
What do we got here Doss?
每个乳房各一个
One for each titty
你是结单套，孩子
You're tying a bowline boy.
不是结胸罩
Not building a bra.
- 有何可笑，下士？ - 说不出来，中士
- What is so funny Corporal?  - Couldn't tell you Sergeant.
来吧
Come on.
来吧女士们，爬起来
Come on ladies. Pick it up.
行动，行动，给我燃起来
Move it. Move it. I wanna see some fire here.
快点
A little hustle.
给我露几手
Show me something.
拼命跑，下！下！下
Run like you need it. Down. Down. Down.
更快！更快！更快
Faster! Faster! Faster!
一起去清洗地道，男孩们
Let's go wash tunnel boys.
现在是时候相信你了
It is got time to trust you now!
行动！行动！行动
Move. Move. Move.
我想看到你赢
I wanna see you won it.
一起来！钻！钻！钻
Let's go. Get in. Get in. Get in.
不要忘记耳后有人，一起来！行动
Don't forget behind your ears. Let's go. Move!
我敢打赌你正享受这样，裸露狂
I bet you're enjoying this naked degenerate.
一起来，快点！快点！快点
Let's go. Hustle. Hustle. Hustle.
行动
Move.
一起来，还等啥，一起来
Let's go. What are we waiting on. Let's go.
把屁股搬起来
Move your ass.
爬木头，翻墙壁，别跟废物亲近
Get the wood. Get the wall. Don't kiss quitters.
加油，加油
Drive. Drive.
- 你没事吧？ - 我没事
- Are you okay?  - I'm fine.
你到底啥毛病？不准休息
What the hell is wrong with you? No one says take a rest.
把屁股搬到终点线，行动
Move your asses to the finish line. Move.
快点，快点
Hustle. Hustle.
让你的屁股跨过该死的线
Get your asses across damn line.
啊，干得漂亮，多斯
Aye, nice work Doss.
这是美国政府给你们每一位的个人礼物
This is a personal gift from the United States government to each and everyone of you.
标准美式步枪
Standard issue U.S. rifle.
三〇口径
Caliber 30.
加兰德步枪
M1！
M1
加兰德步枪
单配弹夹
A clippard.
肩射式半自动武器
Shoulder fired semi automatic weapon
用于把死亡同毁灭带给敌人
designed to bring death and destruction to the enemy.
它将成为你的爱侣
This is to be your lover.
你的情人
Your mistress.
你的小妾
Your concubine.
也许是
Perhaps.
你生命中唯一的真爱
The only thing in life you ever truly love.
伙计们，一起来跳舞
Fellas let's dance.
挑个女孩
Grab a girl.
不要把枪对着前方，我今天不想中弹
Don't point your gun forward. I do not want to be shot today.
不管你多么心痒
No matter how much you are tempted.
把枪放侧边
Place the weapon by your side.
立正
Pay attention.
有问题吗，列兵“玉米杆”
Problem Private Cornstock?
尺寸不对
Is there not one in your size?
还是颜色有问题
Or is it the color that is the issue?
不，中士
No Sarge.
我被告知我不必携带武器
I was told I don't have to carry a weapon.
上前一步列兵，我没听清
Come again step forward Private. I can't be hearing this right.
我很抱歉，中士
Well I'm sorry Sergeant.
我不能碰枪
I can't touch a gun.
究竟是什么问题
What exactly is the problem?
没有问题，只是误会
No problem just a mistake.
- 我参军时就说过  - 这不可能
- I told the army when I joined up.  - It's impossible.
你可知为何不可能，列兵
You know why it's not possible, Private?
不，长官
No, Sir.
因为美军不会犯错
Cause the United States Army does not make mistakes.
若有问题
There's a problem.
你就是那问题
You must be that problem.
我从没想过被派到步兵连
I was never supposed to be sent to a rifle company.
他是个“CO”，长官
He's a CO sir.
你是个“拒服兵役者”
You're a "Conscientious Objector".
- 而你参了军  - 不，先生
- And you joined the army.  - Well no sir.
我是个“良心合作者”
I'm a Conscientious Cooperator.
- 你在愚弄我？多斯  - 不，不，先生，我自愿
- You just screwing with me Doss.  - No. No sir. I volunteered.
我穿制服没问题，向国旗行礼，尽我的义务
I got no problem with wearing my uniform. Saluting the flag and doing my duty.
只是不可以拿枪杀人
It's just carrying a gun and taking a human life.
你不杀人？就这些
You don't kill. That's all.
是的，先生，就这些
Yes sir. That's all.
你知战争中杀戮确实很多
You know quite a bit of killing does occur in a war.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
我是说，战争的本质
I mean that is the essential nature of war.
是，长官
Yes sir.
好吧
Alright.
你对美军还有任何其它要求吗
You have any other requirements for the United States army.
还有什么我们可以做，以确保
Is there anything else that we can do to ensure that
你会满意地跟我们一起呆这儿
you're comfortable with your stay here with us?
他不想在周六工作，长官
He doesn't wanna work on Saturday, sir.
嗯周六是…我是“基督复临安息日”者，因此
Well Saturday is... I'm a Seventh-Day Adventist so.
周六是我的安息日，那就不允许我工作
Saturday is my sabbath so I'm not allowed to work then.
我不认为这会带来问题，你呢？中士
I don't think that poses a problem. Do you sergeant?
我们应要求敌人别在安息日进攻
We should simply ask the enemy not to invade on a Sabbath
因为列兵多斯在此祈祷
cause Private Doss here is a prayer.
好吧，现在我们搞清楚了
Alright. Now we got that clear.
现在让我告诉你我的要求，它们不像
Now let me tell you my requirements. They're not as
你的那么复杂，它们极简单
complicated as yours. They are very simple.
只要你一直呆在这个连队里
As long as you're in this company
由我指挥
under my command
你就得服从我的命令，句号
You're gonna obey my orders Period.
你若在此做不到，我不信你在战斗能做到
If you can't do it here. I can't trust you to do it in the battle.
美军二战条例第八条，判断军人精神方面是否适合服役
我会把你视为符合“第八条例”
I'm putting you in for "Section 8".
美军二战条例第八条，判断军人精神方面是否适合服役
我会让你免役
So I get your discharge.
解散
Dismiss.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我想让你们见见列兵德斯蒙德·多斯
I want you to meet Private Desmond Doss.
显然地
Apparently.
列兵多斯不相信暴力
Private Doss does not believe in violence.
他不愿实施暴力
He does not practice violence.
他甚至不屑摸枪
He will not even deign to touch a weapon.
要知道列兵多斯
You see Private Doss
是一个“拒服兵役者”
is a Conscientious Objector.
所以我恳请你们
So I plead with you.
别指望他在战场上拯救你
Do not look to him to save you on a battlefield.
因为他无疑会
Because he will undoubtedly
太忙于跟他的良心搏斗
be too busy wrestling with his conscience
去协助
to assist.
- 中士，那不是真的，中士  - 列兵
- Sarge, that's not true, sarge.  - Private
原地不动！
as you were.
我意识到你们中有些人对此有着强烈感受
I realize some of you might have strong feelings about this.
那就是男人为何而战
It is what we men fight for.
为了捍卫权利
To defend our rights.
为了保护妇女和儿童
To protect our women and children.
即使列兵多斯的信念
Even if Private Doss's belief
可能会导致妇女和儿童死亡
might cause women and children to die.
所以我希望本连队的每个人
So I will expect every one in this company
给予列兵多斯，充分尊重他应有的尊重
to give Private Doss the full measure of respect he is due.
因为短时间内，他将与我们同在
For the short time he will be with us.
清楚了吗
Am I clear?
是的，中士
Yes, sergeant.
你拿的是啥，戴茜
What you got here Daisy?
- 你知道那是什么吗？ - 像是袖珍版
- You know what that is?  - Just seems kind of small.
这是半大男的半大圣经
It's half-the-Bible for half-the-man.
彼得：耶稣十二使徒之首
看彼得份上，史密提，把圣经还给他
Pete's sake, Smitty give him back his Bible.
彼得：耶稣十二使徒之首
我不记得是在跟你说
I don't remember speaking with you.
你为何不打架
So how come you don't fight?
你自以为优于我们
Do you think you better than us?
不
No.
那么，如果你被攻击，怎么办
Well, what if you're attacked.
哇
Woah.
喜欢吗
Did you like that?
圣经说，你要转过另一边脸
Bible says to turn your other cheekbone.
看见没？跟信仰无关，伙计们
You see I don't think this is a question of religion, fellas.
我认为是懦弱
I think this is cowardice.
显而易见
Plain and simple.
你没事吧？多斯
You alright Doss?
你娘炮？是吗
You chicken shit, that it?
继续
Go on.
打过来
Take a poke.
那好，我不还手
Okay I'm gonna give a free shot.
就是那儿
Right there.
打我多斯
Hit me Doss.
继续
Go on.
啥毛病
What a matter?
上啊
Go ahead.
不打
No?
娘炮
Chicken shit!
- 这是什么？ - 把它给我
- What is this?  - Give me that.
这娘们好看
This is fine looking broad.
- 哇  - 漂亮
- Wooooh.  - Nice.
如今这种娘们
Now this would be the kind of broad
真正的男人才配得上
That deserve a real man.
把它还给我
Give me that back.
请
Please.
请把它归还，史密提
Please give it back, Smitty.
你听得到声音？德斯蒙德
Do you hear voices Desmond?
不，长官
No, Sir.
我理解为上帝在跟你说话？是那样吗
I understand that God talks to you. Is that right?
长官，我没疯
Sir, I'm not a crazy person.
那你觉得大多数人怎么看你
Then how you feel most people regard you
疯子
Crazy person.
我不同别人我知道，只是
I'm different I know that. But
我不愿弄虚作假
I'm not gonna pretend to be something I'm not.
我就是我
I am what I am.
听起来很孤独
Sounds lonely.
你孤独吗
You lonely?
那么你听不到声音
So you don't hear voices.
不，长官
No, sir.
我向上帝祷告，我还
I pray to God and I
觉得他能听见，只是那并非交谈
like to think He hears me but it ain't a conversation.
就像此刻我绝不会假装我们得谈谈
Like how I won't gonna pretend we have right now.
假装？列兵
Pretending, Private?
是，长官，我知道你的打算干嘛
Yes, sir. I know what you really wanna do is
说我是“第八条例者”，把我撵出部队，只是
is give me “a Section 8” draw me out of the army. But
我不是
I'm not.
神明在上
Up above.
我只是信我所信
I just simply believe what I believe.
好吧我尽量去理解
Well I'm trying to understand.
好吗？是上帝叫你别拿枪
Alright? Was it God who told you not to pick up a rifle?
上帝说勿杀人
God says not to kill.
那是他的最重要的戒律之一
That one of His most important commandments.
大多数人把此理解为别谋杀
Most people take that to only don't commit murder.
战争是完全不同的情况
War is completely different set of circumstances.
耶稣说，我把一个新的命令给你们
Jesus said a new commandment I give them to you.
即你爱别人
That you love one another.
有如我爱你
Just as I love you.
我们正在跟撒旦作战，肯定是
This is satan himself we're fighting. Sure as
虔诚的基督徒，你看得出来
good Christian you can see that.
我看得出，长官，这也是我参军的原因
I can see that sir and that is why I joined up.
但是很抱歉，我不能带武器
But I'm sorry I will not bear arms.
他的宗教观确实独一无二，但这些
His religious view is certainly unique but they
不违反第八条例的免役范畴
do not constitute ground for Section 8 discharge.
我该如何让这样的人听命于我
How am I suppose to maintain discipline with a man like that in my unit?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他是一个合法的“拒服兵役者”
But he is a legitimate Conscientious Objector.
他必须被允许作为“军医”提供
He must be allowed to work as Combat Medic provided
他有资格在所有其它区域进行训练
he qualifies in all other areas in his training.
也许我们可帮助缓和他的想法
Perhaps we could help make alleviant his idea.
K.P：清洗打扫整理等繁、重、脏的工作
好，你把他关在兵营去K.P
Yeah you restrict him to barracks in K.P
K.P：清洗打扫整理等繁、重、脏的工作
他扔上帝给你，你扔地狱砸他
He throws God at you. You throw hell right at him.
我要他消失
I want him gone.
禁止洗衣，浴室禁止穿鞋
Scrubbing Clothes NOT ALLOWED, NO SHOES ALLOWED in shower room
多斯，你是个耻辱
Doss your area is in disgrace.
这是个猪圈
It's a pig stock.
- 有何可笑，瑞克？ - 不，中士
- Something funny Riker?  - No sarge.
- 你脑子进大粪了？ - 不，中士
- You got some shit on your mind?  - No sarge.
你们没意识到的
What you men fail to recognize
就是一只队伍并不会比它的最弱者更强
is a unit is no better than its weakest member.
我希望你们记住这教训
I hope you learned that lesson.
本周末不准休息
There will be no passes this weekend.
全部去K.P
You all will be on KP.
现在全体全速徒步二十英里
Right now everybody on full gear for 20-mile hike.
一起去
Let's go.
保持头脑清醒
Get your heads right.
不要自怜
Don't start feeling sorry for yourself.
你们的自怜样叫我恶心
Makes me sick seeing you feel sorry for yourself.
你们这些狗不知累为何物
You dogs don't know what tired is.
我们会继续跑直到我倒下
We gonna keep going till I drop.
来吧，伙计们
Come on guys.
嘿住手！别打了
Hey knock it. Knock it off.
去睡觉
Trying to sleep here.
放开我，放开
Get off me. Get off.
为什么你还在这里
Why the hell you still here?
- 注意！ - 原地别动
- Heed hut.  - As you were.
多斯在哪儿
Where's Doss?
这对你不好，伙计
This isn't good for you buddy.
当然，我参军不是想这样
Sure ain't what I joined up for.
这跟你为何参军无关
It's not about what you joined up for.
有关在此诸位的生活
About the lives of every men in here.
及你的，孩子
And yours son.
是时候退出了
It's time you quit this.
穿好衣服，我送你
Finish getting dress and I'll walk you down.
好了，多斯
It's okay Doss.
别为此羞愧
There's no shame in this.
我们走吧
Let's go.
我有额外的执勤，今天，上午我得去K.P，所以
I got an extra guard duty. Today and I'm on KP this morning. So
我不能
I can't.
好吧，多斯
Alright Doss.
列兵多斯
Private Doss.
你能认出打你的人吗
Can you identify the men that beat you?
不，中士
No sarge.
你是说你不知道是谁打了你
Are you saying that you don't know who attack you?
我从未说过我被打了，中士
I never said I was attacked sarge.
你究竟在说啥？多斯
What the hell are you saying Doss?
你伤得难以入睡
You bruised half your body sleeping.
我睡得很沉
I sleep pretty hard.
本周计划湿训，确保你戴上帽子
Planning on getting wet this week make sure you put on a hat.
我不希望任何人回来尿在奶油里
I don't want anyone back piss in cream.
你不是想要咖啡吗？中士
What you don't want to offer your coffee Sarge.
给你颗枪子儿如何？史密提
How about a shot right now Smitty?
讲讲经验，中士
Speaking from experience Sarge.
你得问你娘，老油条
You have to ask your mom about that Greaseball.
稍息
At ease.
列兵多斯
Private Doss.
恐怕我不能准你的假
I'm afraid I can't authorize your pass.
假期只给通过基本训练的人
This is a furlough for men who had pass the basic training.
尊敬的长官，我过了
Respectfully sir I have.
我申请了此假，三周前
I put in for this furlough three weeks ago.
我要结婚，今天下午
I'm getting married this afternoon.
你步枪不合格
It says you're not rifle-qualified.
我不需要携带步枪，长官
Well I'm not required to carry a rifle, sir.
上校施特尔策，他，他…
Colonel Colonel Stelzer he he...
上校施特尔策规定：
Colonel Stelzer stipulation was
特许多斯作为军医服役
Doss must be allowed to work as a combat medic.
准予他有资格在任何其它区域完成训练
Provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training.
而你在枪械上无资格，列兵
And you have not qualified on the rifle range, Private.
很清楚
Pretty clear.
给我演示下你会拿枪
Show me you know how to handle a rifle.
我就准假
And I'll sign your furlough.
下士坎农
Corporal Cannon.
给列兵多斯你的枪
Hand Private Doss your firearm.
我不会碰步枪，长官
I won't touch a rifle, sir.
我不是要求你，列兵
I'm not asking you Private.
这是个部队指挥官的直接命令
That is a direct order from a company commander.
看上帝份上，多斯
For God's sake Doss.
别再废话，退出
You stop this nonsense and quit.
拒绝
Refuse.
我则没有追索权，只能送你去军事法庭
And I will have no recourse but to court-martial you.
你将在军事监狱度过战争期
And you will spend the duration of the war in military prison.
我不能，长官
I can't, sir.
你愿意等多久，多萝西
How much longer would you like to wait, Dorothy?
我想得足够久
I think it's been long enough.
这真是太遗憾了
I'm so very sorry.
有时男人会临阵退缩
Sometimes men just get cold feet.
有的男人会
Some men might.
但我的德斯蒙德不会
Not my Desmond.
你可能觉得我真是婊子养的
You probably thinking I'm a really son of a bitch.
只在乎规定不关心自己人
Who cares only about regulations and not his men.
可以吗
May I?
我跟任何人一样信任此书
I believe in this Book as much as any men.
跟任何人一样
Just like any men.
我会被良心困扰
I wrestled with my conscience.
但你会怎做，当世上你珍视的一切皆受攻击
But what do you do when everything you value in this world is under attacked.
我不知道，长官
I don't know, sir.
我没法回答那种大问题
I ain't got answer to question that big.
但我感同我珍视的正受攻击
But I also feel like my values are under attacked.
我不知何故
I don't know why.
我不关心你的原则，因为日本人不
I don't give a rat-ass about your principles because the Japs don't.
如果他们有人攻击你和受伤的士兵，你怎么办
If one of them attacks you and some wounded soldiers. What are you gonna do?
用你的圣经揍他
Hit him with your Bible?
我已准备好为大家牺牲
I'm prepare to give my life for my men.
你无法赢得战争即使你牺牲
You don't win wars by giving up your life.
看吧
Look.
我只身到此，因我不愿看到你烂在牢房
I'm only here because I don't wanna see you rotting in a prison cell.
认罪
Plead guilty.
为自己争取法庭怜悯，也许他们会让你回家祈祷
Put yourself at the mercy of the court. Maybe they'll let you go home and pray.
让勇士们去赢得战争
Let the brave men out there go and win this war.
如果我不能说服你，也许她可以
If I can't convince you, maybe she can.
他们不准我打电话你
They wouldn't let me call you.
我知道不是你不打
I know it wasn't your making.
他们对你做了些啥
What did they done to you?
没关系我很好
It's okay I'm alright.
只是打了几下墙还有些失落
Just a couple of rounds with a wall and lost.
他们说你会入狱，德斯蒙德
They're saying you could go to prison Desmond.
甚至更糟
Leaven worth.
一定有别的办法
There must be some other way.
我不知将会怎样
I don't know what that could be.
我做了他们要求的每件事，除了这件事
I done everything they'd asked me except this one thing.
他们一直待我如罪犯，只因我不愿杀敌
They've been treating me like a criminal just cause I won't kill.
你尽了力
You tried.
没人否认
Nobody can say you didn't.
但你在狱中能救谁
But who you gonna save in prison?
可能没人
Probably nobody.
那你为何不拿起笨枪，四处挥挥
Then why can't you just pick up the stupid gun and wave it around.
你不必用枪，只需带枪
You don't have to use it. Just made it half-way.
我不能那样做
I can't do that.
是的，你能，这只是骄傲
Yes, you can. It's just pride.
骄傲跟倔强
Pride and stubborness.
别把你的意志跟上帝的混同
Don't confuse your will with the Lord's.
我一直很骄傲
I've been proudful.
也许我真的很骄傲
Maybe I'm proudful.
但我不知，我怎能独自活着，若不忠于我之所信
But I don't know how I'm gonna live with myself if I don't stay true to what I believe.
看着我们你怎能跟我一起活下去
Watching us how you could live with me.
我想做个男人，如你所见
I wanna be a man and I wanna be in your eyes.
我爱上你
I fell in love with you.
因你不象其他人
Because you weren't like anyone else.
你也不会想那样
And you didn't try to be.
任何时刻都别认为你会让我失望
Do not think for one moment that you'll disappoint me.
我将爱你
I will love you.
无论怎样
No matter what.
我不知他要做啥
I don't know what he's gonna do.
他输定了，无论如何
He loses no matter what.
他们想让他认罪，但这会让他开除军籍
They want him to plead guilty but then it'll get him dishonorable discharge.
否则他就是违抗他们，他必会入狱
Otherwise he fights them he will for sure go to prison.
无论怎样，他们会叫他懦夫，我看不出他怎能那样活着
Either way they'll call him a coward and I don't see how he can live with that.
谢谢你多萝西
Thank you Dorothy.
如果你能跟他谈谈
If you get to talk to him.
告诉他我们爱他，会为他祈祷，会为你们祈祷
Tell him that we love him and that we'll pray for him and we'll pray for both of you.
我会的
I will.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
我当然失去了理智
Of course I'm out of my mind.
你以为我是谁，我疯了
What do you think I am. I'm out of my mind.
请你离开这屋
Will you leave this room.
不要，汤姆，把它放下
Don't Tom. Put it down.
放开我，婆娘
Get away from me woman.
美利坚合众国之印
SEAL OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
有何贵干，先生
May I help you sir?
我想找准将穆斯格罗夫
I wish to speak to Brigadier General Musgrove.
没有预约可不行，那样绝无可能
Not without an appointment you can't. That would be quite impossible.
如能劳你告诉他：下士托马斯多斯将感激一个简短的面谈
If you would kinda tell him Corporal Thomas Doss would've appreciate a brief word.
他在开非常重要的会
He is in a very important meeting.
我跟他在法国贝洛伍德打过仗，他是我队长
I fought with him in France at Belleau Wood. He was my Captain.
求您女士，此事至关重要
Please maam. It's most vital.
仅需一分钟
Be over in a minute.
你将安全到家，就跟没事一样
You'll be home safe and sound like nothing ever happened.
这是列兵多斯的听证会
This is a hearing in the matter of Private Doss.
指控是他违反了其指挥官的一系列直接命令
The charge is disobeying a series of direct orders from his commanding officer.
被告怎么说
How says the defendant?
列兵多斯希望进行无罪答辩
Private Doss wishes to enter a not guilty plea.
是这样吗，列兵？我以为已同意过
Is that so Private? I thought this was agreed.
你想进行某种讨价还价的答辩？
You want to enter some sort of plea bargain.
- 是的，长官，但我改变了主意  - 就这样
- Yes, sir. But I changed my mind.  - Just like that?
你希望进行军事诉讼
You wish to proceed to a court martial.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
那你如愿了列兵
Your on your head then Private.
开始
Proceed.
法官大人
Your honor.
列兵多斯
Private Doss.
挥舞其道德观，有如某种荣誉的徽章
Wave his morality like it's some kind of badge of honor.
他炫耀他的蔑视
He flaunts his contempt.
靠直接违反其指挥官的一系列直接命令
By directly disobeying a series of direct order from his commanding officer.
当这些最优秀的年轻人牺牲自己性命抵御邪恶时
When the very best of our young men are sacrificing their lives against evil.
- 你没事吧？ - 是的
- You okay?  - Yes.
- 他们还在审议？ - 是的，先生
- They still deliberating?  - Yes, sir.
好吧，你把这个拿进去
Okay you go take this in there.
我不能，必须是军人
I can't. It's strictly military personnel.
那你让他们中某个带进去
Well you get one of them to take it in.
他们不会帮忙，他们就等着埋了他
They ain't no help. They're fixing to burying him.
任何军事法院只需问被告一个问题：
There's only one question that any military court need ask of the accused.
你否认违反上校萨斯顿的直接命令
Do you deny disobeying Colonel Sangston's direct orders?
那么，你否认吗？列兵
Well. Do you private?
不，长官，我不否认
No, sir. I don't.
那你为何要质疑它呢
Why are you contesting it, then?
这对你为何如此重要，使你拒绝去
Why is it so important to you, given your refusal to even
触摸武器，即使是在部队中服役
touch a weapon to serve in a combat unit?
因为当日本偷袭珍珠港之时，我视为针对我个人
Because when the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor, I took it personal.
我认识的每个人都愤然参军，包括我
Everyone I knew was on fire to join up, including me.
有两个人在我们镇上
There were two men in my hometown
4-F：二战服役有关的物理，心理，或道德标准
被判4F不合格，他们就自杀了，因为不能服役
Declared 4-F unfit, they killed themselves cause they couldn't serve.
为何？我在国防工厂有份工作
Why, I had a job in a defense plant.
我可以续约，但那样不对
I could've taken a deferment, but that ain't right.
这样不对：别人就该去战斗去牺牲
It isn't right that other men should fight and die
而我只是安全的呆坐屋里，我需要服役，长官
that I would just be sitting at home safe. I need this, sir.
我有能力有激情作为军医服役
I got the energy and the passion to serve as a medic,
应当在其他伙伴当中，毫无危害，只是…
right in the middle with the other guys. No less danger, just...
当每个人都在取命，我是去救命
while everybody else is taking life, I'm going to be saving it.
既然这世界已把自己搞得四分五裂
With the world so set on tearing itself apart,
这对我不算是太糟糕的事
it doesn't seem like such a bad thing to me
去把那些碎片重聚一块儿
to wanna put a little bit of it back together.
抱歉先生，无人准进
Sorry sir, nobody is allowed.
不，你不知，我儿就是被告
No. You don't understand. My son is the defendant.
- 我理解，先生，但是无人准进  - 我有封信
- I understand sir but nobody is allowed  - I have information.
好吧，表达的情感值得称赞
Well, the sentiments expressed are laudable.
指控的事实无可争辩
The facts of the charge seem incontestable so
那边所为何事
What the hell is going on out there?
让他进来
Let him go.
那是一战制服
That's the Great War uniform.
是的，长官
It is, sir.
长官，我得请您过目此信
Sir, I need to show you this.
恕我直言，先生
With respect, sir.
您不再是军人
You are no longer a member of the military.
你不能参加此审议，我很遗憾
You unable to attend this meeting. I'm sorry.
这么说真是这样的了
Is that truly the way it works?
你为国而战
You fight for your country
你失去了无数挚爱，然后你就没用了
You lose so much ever dear to you. And then you're done with?
仅剩制服，无权发声
Uniform's forgotten. You have no voice?
你参战了
You were enlist?
是的，长官，在贝洛伍德
I was sir Belleau Wood.
两次授勋，我看到的，先生
Twice decorated. I see it sir.
我想你是被告之父
I take it you're the father.
我是，长官，托马斯·多斯
I am, sir. Thomas Doss.
那么作为前军人，你知这儿有法律
Then as former military man. You know there are laws here.
长官，我清楚法律，我是，我知我儿受这些法律保护
Sir, I know the law. I am. I know my son is protected by those laws.
它们受宪法约束
They are framed in our constitution.
我相信它们，像他那样
And I believe in them as he does.
那就是为何我曾为捍卫它们而战
That's why I went and fought to protect them.
这就是我所思所为，因为如果不是为此
It's what I thought I was doing because if it wasn't for that
我就不知我到底去那里干了啥，长官
then I have no idea what the hell I was doing there, sir.
谢谢你，下士多斯
Thank you Corporal Doss.
让我看看这信
Let me have the letter.
你得离开
You must go.
被告作为一个“拒服兵役者”的权利，受国会一项法案的保护
The defendant's rights as a Conscientious Objector are protected by an Act of Congress.
他不能被迫放弃这些权利
And he cannot be compelled to waive those rights.
权利包括本案述及之违抗携带武器命令
That includes in this case his disobeying orders to bear arm.
签署，准将穆斯格罗夫，战争服务指挥官，华盛顿特区
Signed Brigadier General Musgrove. War Services Commander, Washington DC.
上校
Colonel.
我撤销控诉
I withdraw the charges.
那么本案驳回
Then this case is dismissed.
列兵多斯，你可自由的投入战斗的地狱烈火
Private Doss you are free to run into the hell fire of battle
无需任何武器保护自己
without a single weapon to protect yourself.
你可恢复原职责
You may resume your duties.
作为军医开始训练
Begin training as a combat medic.
- 他去哪儿了？ - 走了
- Where is he?  - Gone.
出来就走，我请求他留下，说他同样想留下
Straight after. I begged him to stay. I told him he want the same.
你回家后告诉他：我爱他
When you get home you tell him that I love him.
好的
Okay.
你要好好的回到我身边
You better come home to me.
冲绳岛，三月 1945
OKINAWA, MAY 1945
山姆大叔微微笑，平静有如孩子貌
Uncle Sam is smiling. Peaceful as a child
但是切忌让他闹
But never get him rowdy
别唱了，汤姆
Cut it out, Tom.
- 你现在想玩吗？ - 闭嘴
- So now you wanna play?  - Shut up
- 拜托！安静下  - 闭嘴，衰人
- C'mon pipe down.  - Shut up man.
把袜子塞嘴里，小男孩，当我们到那儿时再唱
Put a sock in it boy. You save the choral for when we get there.
司机驾到
Your driver is here.
让路
Give 'em room.
晴空，万里无云
Clear. Clear blue sky.
美国陆军第96步兵师，二战服役
九十六师
96th.
美国陆军第96步兵师，二战服役
他们都剩下些啥？
What's left of 'em.
这些是他们的后备军
These are the guys who replaced them.
我觉得不错，这儿挺好
Seems good to me. It's cool.
安全，中士
All clear Sarge.
队长格洛弗
Captain Glover.
中尉曼维，九十六师
Lieutenant Manville. 96th.
我们被派给您，长官
We've been assigned to you, sir.
好的
Okay.
- 大家给这些伙计弄点吃的  - 是，长官
- Let's get these men some chow.  - Yes, sir.
- 这是中士豪厄尔  - 很高兴见到你，长官
- This is Sergeant Howell.  - Good to meet you sir.
谁是多斯
Who's Doss?
在那儿
Over there.
你是多斯
You Doss?
伊夫·谢克特
Irv Schecter
你和我和“桃子”在此
You and me and Peach here.
是本区仅有的医护人员，所以
About the only medics we got left in this area. So
我想我们将一起工作
I guess we're going to be working together.
你刚从前线来
You just come off the line?
情形如何
What's it like?
我问了情形如何
I said what's it like?
钢锯吗
Hacksaw?
我们攻下六次
We caught it about six times.
六次被他们赶出
Six times they threw us off.
最后一次没留下任何东西可修复
Last time wasn't anything left for something to fix.
他们是畜生
They're animals.
恶臭的畜生
Stinking animals.
小日本不关心他们是死是活
Nips don't care if they live or die.
他们想死
They wanna die.
他们不断袭击你
They keep coming at you.
他们从不放弃
They never gonna give up.
永不
Never.
嘿，伙计
Hey buddy.
日本鬼专门袭击伤员
The Japs deliberately target the wounded.
去掉你所有的红十字标志
Lose all your red cross markings.
小日本极好枪击军医
Nips put a premium on shooting medics.
那白色的靶心
That white's a bull's-eye.
拿去，我给你个新头盔
Here I got you a new helmet.
一码配所有
One-size-fits-all.
这是我们的目标
That's our objective.
钢锯岭
Hacksaw Ridge.
我们占领它，可能就拿下冲绳
We take it. Maybe we get Okinawa.
拿下冲绳，我们就能占领日本
We get Okinawa. We take Japan.
吸口气
Take a breather.
我们的海军朋友会温柔的请他们欢迎各位
Our pals in the Navy are gonna soften them up for us.
那死样没人能活
Nobody can survive that shit.
噢，但他们能
Oh, but they can.
中尉
Lieutenant.
此处的这些掩体，这里和这里，准确吗？
This bunkers here. Here and here. Is that accurate?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
是的，长官，也许他们会从后面看，但这就是全部
Yes, sir. Maybe they are gonna look from the back but that's all.
完全不同，那上边
It's all different. Up there.
[全体进攻]
[All here accounted.]
战士们
Gents.
出发
Move out!
是血
It's blood.
糟透了
No shit.
我们已不在堪萨斯了，多萝西
We're not in Kansas anymore Dorothy.
继续爬
Keep climbing.
这里，来把你的手给我
Here. Come on give me your hand.
让路
Make way.
拉尔夫，把这个给杰索普
Ralph, get this to Jessop.
来了
Incoming!
趴下
Get down!
他们到底在哪儿
Where the hell are they?!!!
我看不到他们
I can't see them!!!
该死的在哪儿
Where the fuck?!!!
军医
Medic!
在这边
Over here!
把手放在这儿
Put your hand right here.
按住肠子
Put your hand on that gut.
来吧，我们帮你找掩护
Come on. We're gonna get you under cover.
继续前进
Keep moving forward.
看不到任何东西
Can't see anything.
是那个吗？
It's that one?
我不知打哪儿
I dunno where to shoot.
好吧，我们上
Alright let's go.
迪诺
Dino!
噢，糟糕
Oh shit!
多斯，迪诺中弹
Doss, Dino's down.
我来了
I'm coming.
让路
Get out of the way!
你受伤了
You hurt?
我很好
I'm fine.
来吧！我帮你
Come on! I got you.
吸气
Breath.
尽量吸气
Just breath.
吸气
Breath.
没关系
It's okay.
尽量吸气
Just breath.
我帮你
I got you.
嘿！嘿
Hey! Hey!
给他一针吗啡再继续前进
Give him a shot of morphine and move on.
他挺不了一天
He's not gonna last a day.
求你，求你了多斯，别，别
Please. Please Doss. No. No.
别丢下我
Don't leave me.
别丢下我，请别丢下我
Don't leave me. Please don't leave me.
我有孩子
I got kids.
求你！别这样
Please! Please dont!
请别丢下我
Please don't leave me!
我不会离开
I ain't going anywhere!
我要带你回家，我会救你，拉尔夫
I'm going to get you home. I got you Ralph.
好吗
Okay!
我会带你回家
I'm gonna get you home.
吗啡来了，吗啡来了
Here's come the morphine. Here's come the morphine.
很快就会起作用，拉尔夫，我们会转移你
Just gonna kick it real quick, Ralph. We gonna get you shifted.
担架
Stretcher!
起来
Get up!
继续前进
Keep moving!
中士，我受伤了
Sergeant. I'm wounded.
你没事
There's nothing wrong with you.
倒霉
Shit!
坚持，小子
Hang on kid.
动起来
Move!
不当士兵就当死人
A soldier who doesn't is a dead one.
我们有个优先级
We got a priority.
优先级？你还没有分类
Priority. You haven't of triage?
- 他会死在我们送他们下去之前  - 你不能肯定
- He'll be dead before we get 'em down.  - You don't know that.
送他下去
Get him down!
那好
Alright!
嗯？
Huh?
- 好吧  - 很好
- Okay.  - Okay.
好吧，走吧
Okay. Go!
没事的老友，我们会送你回家
It's alright buddy. We gonna get you home.
军医
Medic!
救命！救命
Help! Help!
我觉得若我们看不见他们，他们也看不见我们
I figured if we can't see them and they can't see us neither.
救命
Help!
我不能动
I took it bad.
我来了，弗兰克，你伤在哪儿？
I got it Frank. Where you hit?
我认为他们只是自作聪明！
I think they just did smart-ass!
来吧！来吧！用手抓住我这儿
Come on, Come on,give me your hand here.
趴下，长官
Get down sir.
在那儿
Over there!
掩体
The bunkers!
看到了，最好呆下边，长官
I do. Better stay down sir.
发现敌人
I got 'em!
正前方
Dead ahead!
是的，我也看到了
Yeah. I see them too.
准备好所有武器消灭他们
Get ready give 'em everything you got.
我会让武攻队从两侧围剿
I'll sent them a weapon's team to flank them.
抓紧点，你会完好如初
Be there tight. You gonna be right as new.
- 好吧？ - 我来吧，多斯
- Alright?  - I got it Doss.
好了
Got it.
嘿
Hey
你干得可好？
You doing okay?
还好
Okay.
开火
Fire!
上
Go!
婊崽子
Son of a bitch!
干掉他们，接着打
Get 'em. Get on it!
- 遵命长官  - 马上
- Yes sir.  - Now!
烟雾弹
Smoke!
医护兵
Corpsman.
上
Go!
上！“食尸鬼”！往洞里打
Go! Ghoul! Get in the hole.
…母亲
Mother...
上
Go!
要坚强
Be strong!
掩护
Cover!
炸药包
Satchels!
“食尸鬼”
Ghoul?
这儿
Here!
来吧坚持住
C'mon stick it.
坚持住食尸鬼
Stick it Ghoul.
掩护！掩护
Cover! Cover!
崽…
Son of a...
掩护他
Cover his ass!
上
Go!
军医
Medic!
我在这里，用手按住它
I'm here. Put your hand on it.
用手按住它
Put your hand on it!
上！上！上
Go! Go! Go!
“食尸鬼”
Ghoul.
你伤在哪儿？
Where you hit?
我不知
I don't know.
你没伤着头没事的
You not hit in the head that's okay.
你叫啥名
What's your name?
安迪
Andy.
安迪啥
Andy what?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
外号
Also known as?
- “食尸鬼”  - “食尸鬼”
- Ghoul.  - Ghoul.
“食尸鬼”你没事，你没事
Ghoul you're okay. You're okay.
很称职汉子们
Good job men.
干得不错
Good work.
就此过夜，我们守住本地
Take it for the night. We hold this spot.
我们明天消灭剩下的山脊
We mop up the rest of the ridge tomorrow.
好了男孩们
Okay boys.
给自己找个舒适安全窝儿
Find yourself a nice safe hole.
角落或靠近掩体
End or near the bunker.
我们每两小时换次岗
We'll take watch every two hours.
我们不知那边是些啥
We don't know what's out there.
死忠，愚蠢
Heads down, asses lower.
不说英语的全毙了
Shoot anything that don't speak English.
包括“老油条”？中士
That includes Grease Sarge?
尤其是他
Particularly him.
我不关心他是否需要尿尿或大号
I don't care if he needed to take a piss or a dump.
单独去那边可不安全
It ain't safe to go out there alone.
你到底要去哪儿？多斯
Where the hell you going Doss?
那边还有很多伤员，中士
Still more wounded out there Sarge.
我和他一起去
I'll go with him.
聪明点，耳朵放低些
Be smart keep your ears down.
好了，大家找个地儿
Alright let's find a spot.
亨利在首轮十五分钟就挂了
You know Henry dead in the first 15 minutes.
直接挂掉
Just straight off.
是直接挂掉
It's straight off.
彼得森
Peterson.
大力水手
Popeye.
斯坦福和墨菲
Stanford and Murphy.
和平年代子葬父
In peace sons bury their father.
战争时期父葬子
In war fathers bury their sons.
别说丧气话好吗
Wanna stop spouting that crap out?
这帮不了任何人
It don't help none.
是啊
Yeah.
是的，你说得对
Yeah, you got that right.
在此无用
Not here.
嘿
Hey.
给我那个
Give me that.
嘿
Hey!
我们找到个腹部伤员
We got an abdominal wound.
- 小伙子需要血浆  - 明白了，他和我们一起
- This lad is gonna need some plasma.  - You got it. He'll be with us.
我们救了你
We got you.
我们找个窝呆呆
Should we find a hole and dig in?
我觉得行
Sounds good to me.
戴上头盔
Put your helmet on.
你要吃那些
You gonna eat them?
我不吃肉
I don't eat meat.
自取
Help yourself.
当然了，你不吃
Of course you don't.
她是个不错的女子
That's one heck of a dame.
你知道你有她让我们很受打击，是吗？
You know you find that you whack us with her don't you?
是的，我知道
Yes, I do.
别告诉她这些
Don't tell her that.
她不会太喜欢我这样的男人
She won't be much happy with a man like me anyway.
是啊，直到她了解你
Yeah until she got to know you.
我是个混蛋，有时
I'm an asshole sometimes.
有时
Sometimes?
你是对的
You're alright.
这些日本人很卑鄙
These Japs are sneaky.
我值头班，现在你眯会儿
I take first watch. Now you get some shut eye.
地狱之梦
Hell of a dream?
我梦见自己被杀
I dreamed I got myself killed.
我毫无办法
I can't do nothing.
只需步枪
Rifles just do.
它不会咬人
It won't bite.
对，那么
Yeah, well.
看看你周围
Look around you.
经历了我们这些遭遇
After what we've been through.
任何理智的人都会尖叫着找寻武器
Any sane man would be screaming for a weapon.
我从未声称自己理智
I never claimed to be sane.
我爸是酒鬼
My daddy's a drunk.
他屡戒屡犯多年，酒瘾缠身，酒后失态
He fought it for years but it kinda got a hold of him hard and made him mean.
至少你知道何时我曾与十人中的任何一位同在
At least you know when mine could've been with any one of the ten guys
而他们没有一个人该死
And none of them would worth a damn.
所以你妈妈养大了你
So your momma raise you?
我记得她
I knew her.
但她把我丢给孤儿院，在我五岁时
But she gave me to an orphanage when I was five.
再没见过她
Never saw her again.
我知如何快速行动
I know how to act quick.
但现在我识人更快，我则确实看错了你
But now I judge people quicker and I got you very wrong.
我爸只是经常打我跟我哥
My dad used to beat me and my brother just
因为日升又因为日落而打我们
cause the sun rose and whip us cause it sets.
我能忍受那样
I could take that.
但当他打妈妈时
But when he would do it to our momma.
够了！不再
That's enough. No more.
听清楚没
Do you hear me?
扣下那该死的扳机
Pull that damn trigger.
不要，德斯蒙德，住手
Don't Desmond. Stop!
但你并没杀他
But you didn't kill him.
在心里，我杀了
In my heart I did.
这就是为何我向上帝发誓我再也不去摸枪
So that's why I made my promise to God I ain't never gonna touch a gun again.
好吧我不会给你我的，因为你是疯子
Well I ain't giving you mine cause you're crazy.
行动！行动！让你们的屁股离开那儿
Move! Move! Get your assess over there!
- 我们为何不…一起撤！ - 撤！撤
- Why don't we... let's go.  - Go! Go!
回去！撤退！撤
Go back! Fall back! Go!
他们来自地下
They're coming from underground!
长官！长官！这是贝克六队，请求立即支援
Sir! Sir! This is Baker Six request immediate support!
目标是北三零五一五
Target is North Thirty Five One Five
你没注意你在哪儿吗？
Don't you notice where you are?
是的，我有留意究竟在哪儿，但我可不想再呆在这儿
Yes, I notice where the hell we are but I don't expect to be here much longer.
我叫了炮兵打击
I called an artillery strike!
撤退！行动！行动
Fall back! Move! Move!
撤退
Fall back!
还有人
Get some!
掩护我
Cover me!
撤！撤
Go! Go!
啊
Argh!
离开这儿，小子
Get out of here, kid!
过来，孩子
Come here, son!
你知怎做
You know what to do!
保持压住它
Keep pressure on it!
不！不需要血浆
No! Don't need plasma!
把它给他
Give it to him!
在那边
Over there!
我会没事的，去吧
I'll be okay. Go!
去吧
Go!
- 里斯！ - 什么
- Reece!  - What?!!!
- 背他走！ - 收到
- Get on the back!  - You got it!
好的，回头见
Okay see you soon.
来吧！来吧
C'mon. C'mon!
我们马上行动，来吧！来吧
We gotta move right now! C'mon! C'mon!
行动！行动
Move! Move!
我很害怕，我很害怕
I'm scared. I'm scared.
这能止痛
This gonna help the pain.
不！不要！不要！你别这样
No! Don't! Dont'! Don't you do that!
来吧
C'mon!
来吧！史密提留下陪我
C'mon Smitty you stay with me!
我们得一起行动
Let's go we gotta move!
嘿！帮我把他送下去
Hey! Help me get him down.
帮我把他送下去
Help me get him down!
来吧让我们行动，来吧
Come on let's move. Come on.
帮不了你，伙计，他走了
Can't help you buddy. He's gone.
没有，来吧，我们要离开这儿
No. Come on. We got to get out of here.
放下绳子
Down the rope!
下一个
After it.
他要我去哪儿
Where does it He want me?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我听不到你
I can't hear You.
救我
Help me!
好吧
Alright!
有多少
How many?
只有三十二个下来了，长官
32 only came down, sir.
上帝啊
Good Lord.
- 我们四下找找  - 是，长官
- Let sow them up.  - Yes, sir.
哈利
Harry.
我是德斯蒙德
It's Desmond.
我们会医好你，你只需保持呼吸，好吗
We gonna fix you up. You just gotta keep breathing. Okay
上校想见你，长官
Colonel want to see you, sir.
我需要你的吉普
I need your jeep.
你两个留此警戒，提防日本鬼子
You two stay here and keep watch. Keep your eyes peel for Japs.
不行，但是…
No. But the...
留此警戒
Stay here and keep watch!
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
救命！救我
Help! Help me.
当心
Watch out!
我救你
I got you.
把手放上面，保持按住它
Put your hand on it. Keep pressure on it.
我会回来
I'm coming back.
- 好吗？ - 别离开
- Okay.  - Don't leave.
轻些，伙计们，轻些
Easy fellas. Easy.
就放这儿
Here we go.
好了伙计们，一起来
Okay guys let's go.
一、二、三，行动
One-Two-Three. Move.
没关系，我们还在一起
It's okay.All we together
我把你救到这儿了
I got you here
只需坐稳，好吗
Just sit tight, okay.
你没事伙计
You okay buddy.
混蛋，这会起作用
Son of a gun. This is gonn a work
每条腿一个
One for each leg.
我们马上帮你穿好
We gonna get you dress up in a jiffy.
再放你下去
and get you down.
我救你
I got you.
我现在救你
I got you now.
你得相信我
You can trust me.
日本佬
Japs!
等等，我们的人，等等
Hold on. One of ours. Hold on.
一起去，一起去
Let's go. Let's go.
我救你，我救你
I got you. I got you.
来吧
Come on.
我救你，你没事了
I got you. You okay.
你没事了
You okay.
嘿
Hey!
又一个
Another one.
上校，呼叫取消炮击钢锯，不能投弹
Colonel. Call off the artillery attack on Hacksaw. Couldn't pull it in.
还有超过一百人在那儿
There's still over a 100 men left out there.
告诉他们取消炮击钢锯
Tell them to call off the artillery on Hacksaw.
(无线电)埃布尔、贝克、壹，结束
[Radio] Able-Baker-One ,over.
坐下，杰克
Sit down Jack.
我给你喝的
I get you a drink.
只是失去掩护
Just lost our cover.
他们要开始了，我们赶紧行动
They're starting. We gotta move.
刚好
About time.
他们不断下来
They just keep coming.
好的，抬起来
Okay. Pick it up.
我抬这边
I got this.
多斯
Doss.
救命
Help.
救我
Help me.
你必须信任我
You gonna have to trust me.
吸口气
Take a breath.
我们走伙计
Let's go buddy.
我们走
Let's go.
杰克，你不知道你在那儿的人是死是活
Jack. You don't know if your men out there are dead or alive.
没有援军，我们不能回到上边去
We can't go back up there without reinforcement.
你会让剩下的人也送命
You'll end up killing the rest.
那就给我援军
So give me the reinforcement.
我没有新人，我没有任何连队
I don't have any fresh men. I don't have any troops.
三个营被消灭在今天
3 batallions got wipe out today.
新兵到这儿还要一天多
And it'll take more than a day to get men here.
我需要他们早点到
I need them faster than that.
没关系，没关系
It's okay. It's okay.
没事了，没事了
It's alright. It's alright.
没关系
It's okay.
吗啡，好的
Morphine it's good.
嘘
Shhh.
军医，军医
Medic. Medic.
军医，我是多斯
Medic. It's Doss.
我是多斯，安静
It's Doss. Be quiet.
安静
Be quiet.
我们来救你，你伤哪儿
We got you. Where you hit?
我看不见
I can't see.
安静，安静点
Be quiet. Just be quiet.
现在别动
Hold still now.
我救你
I got you.
抓稳
Hold tight.
弄好了
There you go.
试着看，试着看
Try that. Try that.
我以为我瞎了
I thought I was blind.
嘘
Shhh.
冷静
Keep it down.
你能走吗
Can you walk?
我不知
I don't know.
- 因为我们得离开这儿  - 好的
- Cause we gotta get out of here.  - Okay.
好了，我们接住你了
Okay we got you.
我们接住你了
We got you.
嗨，你
Hey, there.
是我，德斯蒙德
It's me Desmond.
医好你
Fix you up.
你准备离开这儿，我肯定
You ready to get out here. I'm sure am.
恳请上帝
Please Lord.
让我再救一个
Help me get one more.
请让我再救一个
Please help me get one more.
再一个
One more.
让我再救一个
Help me get one more.
再一个
One more.
让我再救一个
Help me get one more.
再一个
One more.
来了
Coming through.
这些家伙到底哪来的
Where the hell these guys coming from?
钢锯
Hacksaw.
我以为他们已撤完了
I thought they pulled out.
并非所有
Not all of them.
某疯子在那里把伤员从顶上放下来
Some nuts out there drive the wounded from the top.
甚至放下了几个日本佬
Even lowered a couple of Japs.
他们没能挺得住
They didn't make it
回头直接带给你
Get back with you directly.
轻点，轻点
Easy. Easy.
满了，出发
All set. Move out.
我们走
Let's go.
到这儿来
Get in here.
到处都是日本人
There's Nips everywhere.
婊崽子
Son of a bitch.
列兵“玉米秆”
Private Cornstock.
你一无是处如果不是满带惊喜
You're nothing if not full of surprises.
- 你想要些吗啡？ - 想得很
- You want some morphine.  - Hell yes.
那条或两条
That or both.
好吧
Okay.
来了
There.
给你
There you go.
好吧
Alright.
放松，让我看看
Easy. Let me see.
这样如何？好吧，不坏
How's this? Okay. Not bad.
让我看看
Let me see.
我会做得比这还要糟
I'll make much much than this.
但女孩们还是不会吻你
But girls still won't kiss you.
中士
Sarge.
你在此呆一会儿可好？
You okay here for a while?
好的，我还好
Yeah I'm fine.
尽管离开
Get outta here.
我会回来
I'm coming back.
你准备好了？我们走
You ready? Let's go.
你跟我，来吧
You and me. C'mon.
上尉，有事你得瞧瞧
Captain. Something you gotta see.
整个夜里我们的人被一个个的放下来
Our guys have been coming down in droves all night.
而“好莱坞”在此
And Hollywood's here.
我从没想过还能再见此人
I never thought I'd see that guy again.
来吧跟我来，他在这儿
Come on follow me. He's right here.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell is this?
你好，长官
How you doing sir?
嘿，“帽子”
Hey, Cap.
上尉
Captain.
很高兴看到你，孩子
It's good to see you kid.
上帝保佑，长官
God bless, sir.
你怎么下来的，孩子
How you get down, son?
是多斯
It's Doss.
豪厄尔仍在那儿
Howell's still out there.
豪厄尔和多斯做的
Howell and Doss did this?
不，长官，只是多斯
No, sir. It's just Doss.
- 只是多斯？ - 只是多斯
- Just Doss?  - Just Doss.
对，多斯，那“懦夫”
Yeah Doss the Coward.
你喜欢鞋上的枪，不是吗
You like gun on a shoe ain't ya.
给我这个
Give me this.
现在打靶太迟了，你不觉得
It's a bit late for target practice now don't you think.
跳上来
Jump on it.
你开玩笑吧
You kidding?
不，我来拖你
No, I'm gonna drag you.
一起干吧
Let's do it.
- 好没？ - 好了
- Ready?  - Yeah
我们走
Let's go!
我们有追兵
We got company.
来吧
Come on.
我们得跳
We're gonna jump.
你在耍我吧？“玉米秆”
You gotta be kidding me, Cornstock?
你是结单套，不是结胸罩
You got a bowline, not building a bra.
来吧
Come on!
- 好没？ - 啊哈
- Ready?  - Ah huh.
下去
Get off!
- 放下我！ - 是，中士
- Put me down!  - Yes, Sergeant.
中士豪厄尔
Sergeant Howell.
多斯还在那儿
Doss is still up there.
到底咋回事？
What the hell?
他被日本佬尾追
He's got Japs on his tail.
我们接住他了
We got him.
很好，很好
It's good. It's good.
喔，好了，好了，多斯
Woah. It's okay. It's okay. Doss.
你安全了
You're safe.
好吧
Okay.
德斯蒙德
Desmond.
放松
Easy.
这儿，来吧
Here come on.
坐下
Take a seat.
你受伤了
Are you wounded?
没有
No.
大家立即送这名士兵去医疗篷
Let's get this soldier to a hospital tent right now.
来吧，现在放轻
Come on easy now.
放松，放松
Easy. Easy.
伊夫在哪儿
Where's Irv?
伊夫
Irv.
你是说谢克特军医
You mean Schecter the Medic?
他没能挺住
He didn't make it.
他死于震伤
He died of shocked.
没有血浆
No plasma.
抱歉
Sorry.
我只看到一个瘦小子
All I saw was a skinny kid.
我不知你是谁
I didn't know who you were.
你比任何别的男人报效祖国所做的多得多
You done more than any other men could've done in a service to his country.
我此生从未如此看错人
I have never been more wrong about someone in my life.
我希望有天你能原谅我
I hope one day you could forgive me.
我们明天必须回到上边
We have to go back up tomorrow.
我意识到明天是你的安息日
I realize that tomorrow is your Sabbath.
这些人大多数不相信你所信仰的方式
Most of these men don't believe the same way you do.
他们如此相信
They believe so much
你有多坚信
How much you believe.
你在山脊上的所为就是奇迹
What you did on that Ridge is nothing short of miracle.
他们想要一块
They wanna piece of it.
没有你，他们不会去那儿
They're not gonna go up there without you.
你到底拖延什么，上尉
What the hell is your delay, Captain?
你应该在十分钟前开始进攻
You supposed to begin that assault 10 minutes ago.
我们在等着，长官
We're waiting, sir.
等着啥
Waiting for what?
列兵多斯完成为我们的祈祷，长官
Private Doss to finish praying for us, sir.
- 列兵多斯在为你祈祷？ - 列兵多斯到底是谁
- Private Doss is praying for you.  - Who the hell is Private Doss?
我们去干活
Let's go to work.
趴下
Down!
趴下！趴在地上
Get down! Get down on the ground!
立即趴在地上
On the ground now!
躺下！躺下！我有吗啡
Lay down! Lay down! I got the morphine.
我们走！我们走！我们带这个人离开这儿
Let's go! Let's go. Let's get this man outta here.
走！走
Go! Go!
我的圣经
My Bible.
停下！停下！停下
Stop! Stop! Stop!
我的圣经，我的圣经
My Bible. My Bible.
好吧
Okay.
一号外科器
你回家了，德斯蒙德
You going home Desmond.
我们已拿下钢锯
We've taken the Hacksaw.
等下！等下！德斯蒙德
Hold up! Hold up! Desmond.
德斯蒙德
Desmond.
德斯蒙德·多斯把 75 名伤员于钢锯岭战役中带至安全地带
他是第一个拒服兵役但获得美国“战火中的勇气”荣誉勋章者
德斯蒙德和多萝西结婚，直至她在1991去世
他是自己的英雄，保有特有的谦虚，将所有的功劳归于他的上帝
我一直在祈祷
I was praying the whole time.
我只是开始祈祷上帝请让我再救一个
I just start praying to the Lord please let me get one more.
当我救多一个，我说“好吧，上帝请让我再救一个”
When I got this I said "Alright Lord please help me get one more".
他平淡地说“真正的英雄们都埋葬在那里”
我认为任何人都是错的若要去妥协他人的信念
I would say anyone is wrong to try to compromise somebody's conviction.
我不在乎是军队或者是什么
I don't care it's the army or what it is.
当你持有信念
When you're on a conviction
那不是笑话
That is not a joke.
那就是你
That's what you are.
上尉杰克·格洛弗
即使我对他说那些关于携带步枪的事
Even though I said those things to him in regard to carrying a rifle.
然而他永远不会站在我这边，除非他拿了枪
Then he would never be on my damn side at all unless he had a rifle.
但是从长远来看
But then in the long run.
发现他是一个活着的最勇敢的人
Finding out that he was one of the bravest person alive.
而让他停止挽救我的生命则会是对整件事的讽刺
And then to have him ended up saving my life was the irony of the whole thing.
血顺着这家伙的脸跟眼流下
Blood it ran down through this fellow's face and eyes.
那是当他开始呼喊军医的时候
It was when that he go in and called for medic.
我从水壶取水，拿出绷带
I took the water from my canteen and got some bandages.
我冲洗他的脸
And I wash his face.
当我擦拭
And when I wipe
冲洗他的双眼，眼睛睁开了
Washed up his eyes. Eyes came out
伙计，他顿时亮了
Man, he just lit up.
他说，我以为我瞎了
He says I thought I was blind.
如我没有任何东西多于他给我的微笑
And if I hadn't got anything more to what that smile he gave me.
我不会得到很好的回报
I wouldn't have been well repaid.
德斯蒙德·多斯于二〇〇六年三月去世，享年八十七岁
导演
梅尔•吉布森
代表作《勇敢的心》
中文字幕｜dottob
- Subtitled by CrazyIvan -